RIAJULJANNAH

FRONTEND ENGINEER

0416710711

☐ fjriajul@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Communication Skills, Technical Skills
- VS Code, Flask
- React.js
- Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Express.Js, Restful
- Node.js
- HTML5, CSS, Sass
- SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- MongoDB, Deployments
- Python
- Vanilla JavaScript
- Ability to Work Under Pressure
- Critical thinking and problem solving
- Agile Development, Scrum, Kanban
- Customer Service, Collaborative skill
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Implementation skill
- Cloud Computing
- Git
- Api
- Cross Browser Compatibility

EDUCATION

Diploma of IT, Coder Academy

08/2022 - 02/2023

PROFILE

Riajul is experienced and an ambitious professional working with teams to bring problem-solving approach and powerful technology skills to software development process. She has an experience in developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, jQuery, React and JavaScript. She is willing to seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional development while utilising interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills. She is an enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success. She is consistent and energetic to her work which reflects her passionate dedication to every task she takes on.

EXPERIENCE HISTORY

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

FUTURE FRIENDLY / 03/2023 - 04/2023

- · Developed wireframes, site maps and content inventories for new website design
- · Coded the websites using Next.js, Tailwind, React.js, HTML, CSS, Javascript and did the unit testing in each application
- · Liaised between marketing and IT on web development projects integrating front-end assets to back-end systems
- · Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to customer for a better customer service
- · Make recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals
- · Collaborated with team to improve the web design
- · Worked in a product-focused Agile environment
- · Experienced in working with a Scrum team
- · To enhance the team's performance and efficiency, worked on the technical platform, analysed relevant data that customer facing in the web applications
- · Implemented custom web designs which are multi-device and cross-browser accessible
- Focused on the seamless integration of customer success principles into the UI/UX design with the help of the dedicated team's hustle
- Provided cutting-edge customer support by using digital software and technologies that connected people around the global world through innovative web applications

Bachelor of Sciences in Aeronautical Engineering, Military Institute of Science and Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh

01/2016 - 01/2021

LINKS

Github Linkedin

- · Strived to maintain an efficient professional services and continuous internal system products that seamlessly integrates scalability, ensuring optimal storage utilization for the organization
- · Focused to optimize their programs through seamless integration of web technologies, fostering collaborative environments methodolody that drive innovation

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

BASHUNDHARA GROUP / 10/2021 - 06/2022

- \cdot Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML and CSS
- · Delivered responsive web design projects in Agile framework
- Coded using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms
- · Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems
- · Collaborated with project managers and development team to brainstorm new ideas
- · Maintained website with timely updates
- · Studied user requirements to gain a strong understanding of project initiatives and deadlines
- · Adapted quickly to constantly changing, deadline-driven environment
- · Shadowed developers to learn key details about job duties and tasks
- · Pitched feature improvement to developer team for use in application
- · Built some user friendly Ecommerce websites based on the client's requirements
- · Infused innovation into every aspect by the efficiency of Typescript

Projects

Building Management

Built on PostgreSQL, this was a one-stop application for building management whuch uses SQL server and database.

E-commerce Store

Built on Python, this is an online shopping application, enabling visitors to view, add, remove, update items.

Mental Health

Built on MERN stack, this application enabled visitors to book appointments with psychologists and has cross browser compatibility.

Scam Checker

Built on Next.js and Tailwind. This application will help the users to identify the scam links